Web & Mobile Backend & Frontend Full Stack Developer

Contractor - MaryLine Engineers E.I.R.L

Prof. Romel Gomez

romel@maryline.io
(+51) 980653479

https://www.linkedin.com/in/romelgomez/
https://github.com/romelgomez

https://calendly.com/romel-maryline/30min

Romel is a skilled backend & frontend developer with over 10 years of experience, with a track record of building high-value software solutions. Experienced with tests, and familiar with microservices. He loves collaborating with multidisciplinary teams, delivering exceptional products, and continually seeking to learn new technologies. He seeks a position to bring a combination of technical expertise and forward-thinking innovation, ensuring robust and efficient solutions to drive digital transformation and business success.

SKILLS

- > Back-End: Python, Node, Java, Golang.
- > Front-End: NextJS, React, Angular, Typescript, Jquery.
- > Mobile: Expo, React Native, iOS Swift.
- Database: Postgresql, MySQL, Supabase.
- > DevOps: Bash, Docker, Google Cloud, Pantsbuild.
- > Other: Retool, Databricks, Stripe API, Google Analytics, Databricks Notebooks.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer

maergo.com

Mar. 2024 – June. 2024 Austing, TX · Remote

Responsibilities

- ➤ Build a CVS load view in <u>Retool</u> that accelerates the business data loading time by one week.
- > Build a python scraper that collects and normalizes data from various airlines, and then saves it in Databricks.

Full Stack Developer

2ulaundry.com

Feb. 2020 – Jan. 2024 Charlotte, NC · Remote

Responsibilities

> Build and maintain large software platforms using Next.js, and Expo.

- > Develop three React Native apps: one for drivers to track tasks and to-dos, another for customers to schedule pickups and drop-offs, and a third for operations to keep all activities in the facilities in sync.
- > Participate in an on-call rotation to support production systems and investigate issues when they occur.
- > Write high-quality code that is well-tested, secure, and maintainable.
- > Contribute directly to efforts through building features and frameworks, conducting code reviews, and participating in architecture and system design discussions.
- > Design and develop solutions able to process large volumes of data.
- > Lead and participate in positioning our entire software stack both application and DevOps-related for success as we transition from a startup to a large organization.
- > Be instrumental in the transition from our monolith into Service Oriented Architecture.

Full Stack Developer

Rextie.com

Sept. 2018 – Feb. 2020 Lima, Peru · On Site

Responsibilities

- > Provide mentorship and guidance to junior developers, helping them grow their skills and knowledge.
- > Write clean and reusable unit tests, integration, and end-to-end test development.
- > Lead by example in the practice and promotion of excellence in software engineering.
- > Help with root cause analysis, which may identify issues in the reporting, front end or even requirements.
- Collaborating with various cross-functional teams like design, product management, backend architects, and development teams to validate prototypes and to create elegant, usable, responsive, and interactive interfaces that meet client requirements.

Full Stack Developer

MercadoChevere.com

Dec. 2014 - Sept. 2018

Maturin, Venezuela · Remote

Responsibilities

- > Design and implement JAVA-based microservices for managing binary tree structured product categories, ensuring scalability and performance.
- > Develop APIs for category management, allowing seamless integration with front-end interfaces and third-party services.
- Architect database schemas to efficiently store and query hierarchical product data, leveraging binary tree structures for optimized access.
- > Collaborate with front-end developers to ensure APIs meet the dynamic needs of the user interface, enhancing user experience.

> Conduct thorough code reviews to maintain high code quality, focusing on readability, reusability, and maintainability.

EDUCATION

Professor of Informatics
University UPEL IPM | Aug. 2016
Maturin, Venezuela

INFORMATION

Languages: Fluent in English and Spanish.

As a dedicated Full Stack Developer with a passion for problem-solving and continuous learning, I am confident in my ability to contribute to your team's success. I look forward to discussing my skills and experiences that align with your needs. Thank you for considering my application.